Mohammad Mouaz El Mulki

Senior Front-End Developer

EXPERIENCE

Turnsole, UK - Remote

Senior Front-End Developer | Jul 2023 – Present

- Provide mentorship and guidance to a team of front-end developers.
- Review and assess code contributed by team members, ensuring adherence to coding standards, performance, and best practices.
- Establish and maintain coding guidelines to maintain code quality.
- Actively participate in developing our ERP system using React, TypeScript, GraphQL, and Material-UI (MUI) technologies.
- Work closely with the Quality Assurance (QA) team to ensure the reliability and stability of our software.
- Maintained detailed documentation for code, APIs, and development processes.

L-One Systems, Darmstadt, Germany - Remote

Senior Front End Developer | Dec 2021 – Present

- Writing application interface codes using TypeScript following Next.js workflows with automation test with Cypress.
- Build and update the company's website with the provided design with Headless CMS & Next.js.
- completed a project that increased the website speed by 500% and reduced the page load time from 15 seconds to 3 seconds using JAM Stack.

LUCIDLY, UAE - Remote

Senior Front End Developer | Mar 2022 – Apr 2023

- Proficient in developing visually appealing and responsive user interfaces for web and mobile applications using React and React Native.
- Create reusable UI components and libraries to ensure consistent application design and functionality.
- Conduct thorough testing and debugging to ensure high-quality, bug-free software.
- Collaborate closely with UX/UI designers and product managers to translate project requirements into effective front-end solutions

EDUCATION

Microverse, San Francisco (Remote)

Full Stack Web Development | 2020 - 2021

- Microverse is an EdTech company that trains software developers internationally. It raised \$12 Million USD in its series A.
- Spent 1400+ hours mastering algorithms, data structures, and full-stack development while simultaneously developing projects with JavaScript, React, Redux, and Ruby on Rails.
- Developed skills in remote pair programming using GitHub, industry-standard git-flow, and daily standups to communicate and collaborate with international remote developers.

GitHub | LinkedIn

mouaz.almolkey@gmail.com +971 58 54 84410

SUMMARY

Front-end developer specialized in Front-End and skilled in **JavaScript**, **HTML5**, **CSS3**, and **TypeScript**.

SKILLS

Front-end Frameworks: Reactjs, Vuejs, Nextjs

JavaScript Libraries: ¡Query, Threejs

UI frameworks: MUI, ChakraUI, Ant Design

Testing frameworks: Jest, Cypress

CSS frameworks: Tailwind CSS, Bootstrap 5 **Tools & Methods:** Git, Web3, GraphQL, JAM Stack,

Headless CMS

Languages: Arabic- English (Business Professional)

PROJECTS (+20)

ECM Club:)

The scientific training and updating community is dedicated to health professionals, handling more than 1000 users daily.

Built with: (React JS, Redux, Typescript) | **Used Tech:** (Tailwind, AWS) | **Related to (**Axenso)

L-One Systems

A Website for introducing L-One Systems company to the users. Web pages that are generated using **Next JS** and **headless CMS (JAM Stack)** with SSG (**Server Side Generator**).

M-Cultivo

M-Cultivo is an industry-leading provider of ERP (Enterprise Resource Planning) solutions tailored specifically for the coffee production sector **Built with**: (React, TypeScript)| **Used Tech**: (GraphQL, MUI)| **Related to** (Turnsole)

More Projects Available